{"test_questions": [[{"question": "VDRL test is an example of", "opta": "Tube test", "optb": "Ring test", "optc": "Slide test", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Weil-Felix reaction is based on sharing of antigens between", "opta": "sheep RBCs and EB virus", "optb": "mycoplasma and human O group RBCs", "optc": "rickettsial antigens and antigens of certain strains of Proteus", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Agglutination reaction is more sensitive than precipitation for the detection of", "opta": "antigens", "optb": "antibodies", "optc": "complement", "optd": "antigen-antibody complexes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Precipitation reaction is relatively less sensitive for the detection of", "opta": "antigens", "optb": "antigen-antibody complexes", "optc": "antibodies", "optd": "complement", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which of the following case a large lattice is formed?", "opta": "Antibody is in excess", "optb": "Antigens and antibodies are in optimal proportion", "optc": "Antigen is in excess", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ring test is used for", "opta": "C-reactive protein test", "optb": "Ascoli's thermoprecipitation test", "optc": "typing of streptococci and pneumococci", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Precipitation reaction can be converted into agglutination reaction by coating soluble antigen onto", "opta": "bentonite particles", "optb": "RBCs", "optc": "latex particles", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Commercially available ELISA kits are used for the detection of", "opta": "rotavirus", "optb": "hepatitis B surface antigen", "optc": "anti-HIV antibodies", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Monoclonal antibody production requires", "opta": "mouse splenic lymphocytes", "optb": "mouse myeloma cells", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Quellung reaction is used for typing of", "opta": "Klebsiella pneumoniae", "optb": "Streptococcus pneumoniae", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fluorescent treponemal antibody test is an example of", "opta": "indirect immunofluorescence", "optb": "direct immunofluorescence", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Counter-immunoelectrophoresis is used for the detection of", "opta": "Meningococcal antigen", "optb": "Hepatitis B surface antigen", "optc": "Alpha-fetoprotein", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The test (s) based on the principle of toxin neutralization is/are", "opta": "Nagler's reaction", "optb": "Schick test", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Slide agglutination reaction is/are useful for the identification of the culture(s) of", "opta": "Shigella", "optb": "Vibrio cholerae", "optc": "Salmonella", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Amount of various immunoglobulin classes can be measured by", "opta": "double diffusion in one dimension", "optb": "single diffusion in two dimensions", "optc": "single diffusion in one dimension", "optd": "double diffusion in two dimensions", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}